Details

Address

Tehran, Iran

Phone

+98 912 956 42 05

Email

DarvishiParham14@gmail.com

Links

Linkedin GitHub

Languages

English: Advanced Persian: Native

Technical Skills

Programming languages

C# VB.net TypeScript

Framework and technologies

Angular CLI .NET 6 Web API gRPC

Windows Application

Azure DevOps
Design Patterns
Docker
Microservices
Entity Framework

SQL Server

NUnit Ocelot RabbitMQ

Web Design

HTML CSS JS Jquery Bootstrap SCSS

Version Control

GIT TFS

Project management

Jira

Parham Darvishi

Software Engineer

Summary

Parham Darvishi is a software engineer based in Tehran, Iran with **over 5 years of experience**. Parham holds a **bachelor's degree in computer science** and believes personal and professional growth are key to growing a business. Translating the needs and stories of users into effective processes and software solutions that streamline daily lives is a source of enjoyment. Parham is committed to making steady progress toward goals and has a strong understanding of effective solutions.

Work Experience

Software Engineer, HooshoDanesh February 2021 - Present Tehran, Iran

As a senior technical expert on the Emta project, managed a 6-person team for authenticating and authorizing users which had a significant impact on the project:

- Strengthened software's changeability by implementing microservices patterns and clean architecture, resulting in a 40% reduction in the time required to implement changes.
- Created the core domain of the platform using a well-designed template, saving 25% of the development time.
- Implemented domain-driven design to decrease the coupling between services, leading to a 30% increase in the overall system stability.
- Adopted an event-driven approach to reduce direct service calls, resulting in a 20% improvement in system performance.
- Introduced continuous integration and delivery to accelerate product delivery, resulting in a 50% reduction in time to market.
- Aligned the team's vision and mission with that of the company and products by maintaining regular communication with third-party companies, resulting in a 100% successful launch rate.

Technical skills: .NET 6, web API, C#, Microservices, Design Pattern, Swagger, Hangfire, Docker, ADO.Net, SQL Server, Angular, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, TFS, CQRS, IIS

Software Engineer, ICE

April 2019 - January 2021 Tehran, Iran

As a technical expert on the ICE project, a financial validation platform, prepared the test space and offered technical support to project partners. Contributions to the project included:

- Developed one Progressive Web Application (PWA) and two dashboards (admin and customer), increasing user engagement by 20%.
- Refactored 10 backend services using C#, design patterns, and SOLID principles (migrating from VB.Net), resulting in a 30% improvement in code readability and decreasing maintenance time by 25%.
- Improved test coverage by 35% by employing a Test-Driven Development (TDD) approach and writing 250 unit tests, resulting in faster error detection and a 20% reduction in bug reports.
- Maintained and enriched 15 BTB services, ensuring services optimal performance and system availability.

 Technical skills: Angular, Typescript, Swagger, Monolithic architecture, C#, Design Patterns, SQL Server, Postman, ASP.Net Razor page, .NET web API, Bootstrap, HTML5, and CSS3.

Full-Stack Developer, Ibiar

March 2017 - March 2019 Tehran, Iran

As a technical expert of the team that launched Biar in February 2017, provides retail goods online:

- Revamped the software design by employing clean architecture and a well-layered approach, resulting in a 30% reduction in development time and an improvement in product delivery.
- Designed a mobile-friendly layout that increased store traffic by 25%, boosting sales revenue.
- Enhanced the customer experience by implementing a client-side single-page application framework, leading to a 20% increase in customer satisfaction.
- Optimized price and product notifications using SignalR, resulting in a 15% reduction in customer complaints and an improvement in customer retention.
- Collaborated closely with engineers, designers, and product team members to reach project milestones on time and within budget.

Technical skills: Monolithic, VB.NET, ASP.net Razor, SQL Server, SignalR, JQuery, HTML5, SCSS, Bootstrap

Education

Azad University Central Tehran Branch, Bachelor of Computer Science